Matt never saw her coming... but all his friends had!
The Girl Next Door is a comedy, romance film directed by Luke Greenfield.
Exceptionally ambitious high schooler Matthew has aspirations for a career in politics
when he falls in love with his gorgeous 19-year-old neighbor, Danielle.
But Matthew's bright future is jeopardized when he
finds Danielle was once a porn star.
As Danielle's past catches up with her, Matthew's love for
her forces him to re-evaluate his goals.
Matthew Kidman, played by Emile Hirsch.
Danielle, played by Elisha Cuthbert.
Kelly, played by Timothy Olyphant.
Eli, played by Christopher Rodriguez Marquette.
Klitz, played by Paul Dano.
Hugo Posh, played by James Remar.
The Girl Next Door is a 2004 American romantic sex comedy film directed by Luke Greenfield and written by David Wagner, Brent Goldberg, and
Stuart Blumberg, and starring Emile Hirsch, Elisha Cuthbert, Timothy Olyphant, James Remar, Chris Marquette, and Paul Dano.
The story follows Matthew Kidman, a high school senior who falls in love with his new
neighbor, Danielle, and discovers she is a former adult film actress.
Development for The Girl Next Door began as early as 2001.
The film's screenplay was partly inspired by Risky Business (1983).
Principal photography occurred primarily in Los
Angeles County, California and Las Vegas.
The film features cinematography by Eric Alan
Edwards and a score by Paul Haslinger.
The Girl Next Door premiered at the Texas Film Festival on February 18, 2004, before being
theatrically distributed nationwide by 20th Century Fox on April 9, 2004.
It received mixed reviews, with praise for its performances
but criticism for tonal inconsistencies.
Though it underperformed at the box office, The Girl Next Door later gained a cult following through home media and
television, with retrospective appreciation for its genre subversion and portrayal of the adult entertainment industry.
The film explores themes of high school, porn actor,
pornographic video, school party, blonde.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.